

J. DREW SMITH USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER

PORTFOLIO

jdrewsmith.com

EMAIL

joseph.drew.smith@gmail.com

PHONE

(801) 874-4988

ABOUT

I am driven by a burning curiosity and a determination to improve people's lives through design. My experience as an Industrial Designer taught me how empathize with users and recognize their pain points. My experience designing software has taught me to think systematically and to test and measure the success of new designs.

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM CLOUD - UX DESIGNER

Austin, Texas

Design security features and services which are distributed through the Bluemix and SoftLayer Platforms. June 2015 - Present

FAHRENHEIT DESIGN - ID INTERN

Austin, Texas

Worked closely with the Dell Enterprise designers, other smaller local startups, and internal projects. June 2014 - September 2014

WHIRLPOOL ADVANCED DESIGN - ID INTERN

Chicago, Illinois

Involved in all parts of design process for blue-sky products as the only intern on the advanced design team. January 2014 - June 2014

BYU ATHLETIC DEPARTMENT - GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Provo, Utah

Created marketing material for print, web, social media, and branding installations in the athletic facilities. June 2013 - January 2014

BYU LEARNING SUITE - UI/UX DESIGNER

Provo, Utah

Designed new workflow, features, and UI elements for BYU's internal learning management software. June 2012 - April 2013

EDUCATION / TRAINING

From June 2015 to September 2015 IBM Design Bootcamp

IBM Design Austin.

BFA in Industrial Design.

From September 2009 to April 2015

Brigham Young University - Provo, Utah.

From January 2015 to April 2015

UX Design Apprenticeship on development of learning simulation software.

Professor Derek Hansen, Brigham Young University - Provo.

From September 2014 to April 2015

Design Research Assistant on "Fragrance and Color" study.

Professor Bryan Howell, Brigham Young University - Provo, Utah.

From August 2013 to September 2013

International Study Abroad.

Milan, Italy; Paris, France; London, England.